Ju-on : The curse of one who dies in the grip of a powerful rage .
It gathers and takes effect in the places where that person was alive .
Those who encounter it die , and a new curse is born .
JU-ON : The Grudge .
" Rika . "
" Social Welfare Center . "
Thanks for the effort .
Well then , could you write your name and the time here ?
Yes .
Please .
Thank you .
Rika !
It 's this .
What ? By myself ?
I 'm sorry . There 's no one else around .
But ...
Whose case is it ?
I can 't reach him at all .
He took off with the key . And hasn 't come to the office . I 'm in a bind .
I 'm just a volunteer ...
Don 't worry . Don 't worry . You 're used to this .
Oh , Mr. Hirohashi ...
Yes .
I found Mr. Goto .
Goto ?
Come on . Please ? Please ?
Just look in on her . Here .
But ...
I 'll buy you dinner .
What ? You don 't have to ...
" Tokunaga . "
Hello . Anybody home ?
I 'm from the Social Welfare Center ...
I 'm coming in .
Grandma ?
Are you all right ?
You 're Ms. Sachie . Right ?
I 'm here to help out in place of Mr. Takahashi .
My name is Rika Nishina .
Come here .
Ms. Sachie !
Who is that boy upstairs ? !
Someone was locked up in a closet !
Yes .
I didn 't hear anything about a child ...
Yes . He 's still upstairs .
Yes .
I told you . They haven 't come home yet !
But ...
Yes .
Yes . I understand .
We 're not home right now . Please leave your name and message .
Hello ? It 's Hitomi .
Hello ? Is Kazumi there ?
How is Mother 's health ?
I 'm worried . So please call .
Little boy . What 's your name ?
Toshio .
Oh . Your called Toshio .
Um .
My name is ...
What ?
Ms. Sachie ?
I told her .
I told Kazumi .
I told her over and over .
Ms. Sachie , what 's the matter ?
Ms. Sachie , let 's lie down . Okay ?
Again and again . I told her .
Just the way you said to .
Please stop tormenting me .
Ms. Sachie ...
" Katsuya . "
Good morning .
Mom sure sleeps late these days .
That 's because she 's making a commotion all night .
Wha ' ?
It 's been every night .
It 's fine if you can sleep , but put yourself in my shoes being kept awake .
I wonder if it 's because we moved .
I 'll talk to the welfare worker . After all , we 're paying for him to come here .
A waste of time . Your mother 's always courteous to other people .
Okay . Okay .
Try to get along .
You 'll be home early . Right ?
What ?
Didn 't you say Hitomi is coming ?
Oh . Yeah .
You already forgot !
Is it Friday already ?
Get it together .
Hurry home .
Okay .
I 'm going .
I think it was like this yesterday ...
Oh . Mother !
Just tell me if you need something !
Who 's that ?
Who are you ?
I 'm home !
Is Hitomi here ?
Kazumi ?
Mother ?
Mother . Where 's Kazumi ?
What is she up to ?
Kazumi !
Kazumi ?
Kazumi .
Are you here ?
Kazumi ?
Kazumi !
Hey !
What 's wrong ? What happened ?
Come on .
What ?
Hang on . I 'll call an ambulance .
What are ... ?
What are you doing here ?
Kazumi .
Good evening .
I 'm coming in .
Kazumi ?
Mother . How are you ?
Where 's Kazumi ?
Please wait .
I 'll get dinner ready .
Kazumi ? Is that you ?
Brother ?
Brother . Don 't scare me like that !
Where 's Kazumi ?
Kazumi went out for a bit .
Something urgent came up .
Urgent ? Not shopping ?
She 's coming right back right ?
Hitomi . I 'm sorry but today isn 't a very good time .
Wait . Why ?
Brother , is something wrong ?
She had another man .
What !
And she was hiding it from me .
That 's not my child . That 's not my child .
That 's not my child . That 's not my child . That 's not my child .
What are you talking about ?
Brother !
Look . Just go home . Okay ?
Wait . Are you okay ?
Yeah . I 'm fine . So leave me alone for a while .
" Hitomi . "
We 're not home right now . Please leave your name and message .
Hello ? It 's Hitomi .
- Thanks for the effort . - Thanks for the effort .
Hello ? Is Kazumi there ?
How is Mother 's health ?
I 'm worried . So please call .
" Katsuya Tokunaga . "
Hello . Brother ? I just called your house .
Hello ? Brother ?
Look . Stop this weird joke !
Sorry . I just hung up .
Who 's there ?
The 5th-floor Ladies ' Restroom right ?
Yes .
I 'll go take a look .
You wait here .
Okay ?
Excuse me !
Yes ?
Hello ? It 's me .
Brother ?
I 'm in front of your condo building . What was your unit number ?
Unit 702 . Please hurry !
Brother !
In addition , bats , crickets ...
wild birds not seen here before , common harmless snakes .
Among 54 discoveries including a 2.5-meter cast-off snakeskin ...
" Toyama . "
Hello . Anybody home ?
Grandma ?
Huh ?
Rika ?
Rika !
Mr. Nakagawa ...
Hey .
Phone him .
Yes .
It 's above here .
Rika ...
Rika !
Are you okay ?
Yeah . Sorry Mariko .
Did you miss school today ?
No Problem . I 've got all the credits I need .
- Okay . - More important , what happened ?
I don 't really understand it too well myself .
Was Hirohashi asking too much of you again ?
And you couldn 't say no ?
Yeah .
You 're not the one that should be nursed !
Thank you Mariko .
I 'll go buy something to drink .
So that was the first time you 'd been there ?
Yes . The first time .
And the child you say you saw at that house ...
Did you find him ?
No .
Not yet .
Toshio ...
What ?
I 'm sure he said his name was Toshio .
Toshio ?
Ms. Nishina , the Tokunagas don 't have any children .
What ?
But ...
then what about that photograph ?
There should have been a family picture in the house .
That wasn 't a photo of the Tokunagas .
Then who was it ?
We 're investigating it now .
Mr. Detective ...
did something happen there ?
Excuse me .
Before the Tokunaga family ...
other families and relations that lived in that house have died or disappeared .
All of these ?
What about the sister of Katsuya Tokunaga ?
We haven 't had contact .
And a security guard in the building where she works is dead .
And ...
please look at this .
Husband Takeo Saeki killed his wife Kayako there .
Later , Takeo was found dead on a nearby road by a neighbor .
Kayako Saeki .
Twenty eight at the time . Housewife .
She and Takeo had one son between them .
" Toshio . "
Regarding where Kayako 's murdered body was found ...
alas it was up there in the attic .
" Slaughter , Death in Attic ... "
Daddy ! Welcome home .
I 'm home , Izumi . Where 's Mommy ?
She went shopping .
- Is that so . - Yeah .
- If you don 't get home , she 'll be angry again . - It 's Okay . Come over here .
Huh ? What ?
Hurry ! Hurry !
Hurry !
What is it ?
Look at this .
Huh ? What is it ?
- Did you draw those ? - Yep !
Um . This is the Prince of the Land of Angels .
That 's the Princess of the Land of Angels .
And that 's their baby .
I see .
And what 's this ?
Are you Mr. Yuji Toyoma ? I 'm Igarashi of the Yahara Division .
Ouch !
What is it ?
It 's regarding the Saeki investigation you used to head ...
I have some questions .
Izumi . Head on home .
Yeah .
I quit a long time ago .
Will you leave me alone ?
People have died in that house again .
You 're the only one left that I can talk to about that case .
Izumi ! What are you doing there ?
Did you clean the bath ?
What ?
Today is your turn , right ?
- Yeah , okay . - Hurry up .
Is what you saw at the Tokunaga house ...
this child ?
Yes .
Take a good look .
There 's no mistake ?
Yes . It 's him . Did you find him ?
No .
This boy went missing five years ago and has never been found .
If he were alive somewhere today , he 'd be 11 years old .
Huh ?
Mr. Nakagawa .
This is Mr. Yuji Toyama .
Oh .
He was in charge of that case ...
Thank you very much .
Yes .
I 'm Nakagawa . Come in .
Hitomi Tokunaga , younger sister of Katsuya Tokunaga who lived in that house .
After this , she disappeared at home .
Someone in her building witnessed her come home .
Get it .
They found Hirohashi 's body .
The man who found Rika is dead .
What ?
Mr. Toyama .
Yes .
Please wait a moment .
Izumi . You 're a cowardly chicken !
Hey , what 's this ?
Sake .
What 's this doing here ?
Wow ! Awesome . What a house !
This is not sake .
What 'll we do ?
I 'm going home !
Wait ! There 's no problem !
You 're running out on us ?
Izumi !
She is such a coward .
But you know , that 's the way she is .
And you know , these days she hangs with Chiharu .
No good . She hasn 't returned home .
Where could she have gone ?
What 'll we do ?
Did she really go home ?
I can 't believe it .
Hey , Ayano . Look from there .
Yeah .
Hey ! She 's there !
She 's by the gate . She looks deep in thought .
She 's that scared .
Maybe she 's paranormal .
She didn 't have to run away !
Downer .
Yeah .
What was that ?
What ? What 's wrong ?
Izumi really went home .
What ?
Mr. Toyama .
Mr. Toyama !
Mr. Nakagawa !
Let me out !
Get a grip !
A grip !
Mr. Toyoma !
What happened !
No !
I 'm scared !
" Izumi . "
What 's today 's first hour ?
Wasn 't it English ?
That means Sekine from the morning !
- The worst . - The worst .
Don 't you think he speaks weird English ?
It 's weird .
The pronunciation is probably all wrong .
- Yeah . - Yeah .
Is it comprehensible ?
Like , " can you really speak English ? "
- Yeah . It 's a bit much . - Totally .
Izumi ?
What ? Oh .
What 's wrong ?
No . Nothing .
" Searching for Missing Friends . "
Isn 't this Izumi ?
No it 's not .
Izumi , find it ?
I don 't know yet .
Look . You 're here .
Oh yeah .
- Hey . Move ! - Owl .
Many thanks .
Hey Teach !
Yeah . What is it ?
Toyama ? What 's wrong ?
There 's not one photo with Izumi in it .
What 's going on here ?
That 's impossible . Did you really look ?
It 's not there .
We checked over and over . Right ?
Is that right . I 'll have the negative checked . Can you wait a little longer ?
Bye .
- What 's a little longer ? - Ouch ouch ouch .
Stop pulling .
- Don 't you feel sorry for Izumi ? - It 's going to stretch .
It 'll take about a week .
Why 's it take so long ?
I 'm busy !
A woman 's body has been found in the attic of a deserted house in Nerima Ward .
The body has been identified as that of previously missing ...
Rika Nishina . A 23 year-old welfare nurse .
As no marks were found on the body ...
Here .
Thanks .
You 're late !
Don 't blame me !
We 're about to go to Izumi 's .
Let 's see . I 'll come with you .
Hey !
Teacher doesn 't have to come . Bye .
We 'll return it tomorrow for sure .
I 'll leave Toyama to you .
Come on . Let 's see !
- No ! - What ?
We 'll see them with Izumi .
Wait , but ...
- Hurry , let 's go . - What 's inside ?
You 're Izumi 's friends ?
Izumi ? It 's Chiharu . Miyuki is here too .
The photos are done so we brought them .
Can we come in ?
Isn 't it a little dark ?
Yeah .
Don 't !
Izumi .
What 's happened ?
Izumi ?
The three of them ...
look in .
That 's why .
What ? What three ?
Saori and the rest .
When the three disappeared ...
I was with them .
Why didn 't you ...
I was scared !
Scared of what ?
The day we came back from the school trip ...
Saori started saying ...
" there 's a haunted house nearby . Let 's go . "
Haunted house ?
Where could something like that be ?
I can 't remember !
Wait . Why ? That 's not possible !
I wanted to !
Izumi ! What 's going on ?
Please tell us .
It was strange even before we went in .
The place felt strange .
Izumi , were you paranormal ?
I don 't have any sort ...
It 's nothing like that .
You two must not go near .
Saori and the others were having fun but ...
I didn 't want to stay there .
I left that house alone .
I was so scared I ran away by myself .
That 's why .
Saori and them were left there ...
Izumi ! Get a hold of yourself ! Izumi ! Get a hold of yourself ! Izumi !
Get a hold of yourself !
Close it !
Close it ! Just close it !
Close it 'll !
That 's what my husband was like before he died .
In the same way , he sealed all the windows .
Does Izumi know about that ?
I haven 't told her anything .
Oh , the photographs .
What is this ?
" Searching for Missing Friends . "
No !
Chiharu !
Who are you ?
Daddy .
That time ...
I saw you Daddy .
" Kayako . "
Yes hello ?
Hey Mariko ! Long time no see !
Yeah .
What 's going on ?
I see . That 's really rough .
Peek-a-boo !
Peek ...
a-boo !
Tomorrow ? Sure , no problem .
Yeah . Yeah . I understand .
Yes . I 'll see you .
Okay .
Mr. Saito . Sorry to keep you waiting .
Mr. Saito , I heard you 're going to have a great grand-child .
Peek-a-boo !
Peek ...
a-boo .
Mr. Saito ?
Peek-a-boo .
Thank you .
Rika !
Mariko !
How have you been ?
What ? Did you change your hair ?
I cut it .
So cute !
I think around Sunday . Well ?
Sunday ? Sunday is alright .
- Really ? - Yeah .
There just happened to be two tickets inside .
" Please take Ms. Nishina . "
Really ?
What ?
Rika , you liked Toyoshima your senior year didn 't you ?
Huh ?
Rika , it 's so easy to read your face .
Welcome .
This is the menu .
Please let me know when you 've decided .
There 's already one problem kid in my new class .
Really ?
He hasn 't come to school once . What do you think ?
And his parents ?
I can 't contact them . That 's the problem .
I see . But don 't you think there 's a reason ?
But don 't you think they could at least contact me ?
At this rate , I won 't finish my home visits .
That 's right , home visits .
All the other classes have finished . I 'm the only one left .
Is that right .
What ?
Mariko , you 've turned into a real teacher .
What about you , Rika ?
I wonder . I can 't really tell ...
What happened ?
I just felt something ...
Rika ?
Rika ? Are you okay ?
Hey Rika ?
Hey Rika !
Rika !
Rika , what 's the matter ? Are you alright ?
Yeah ...
Hello . This is Nishina .
Hello Rika ?
Oh , Mariko ? I 'm sorry about today .
You scared me all of a sudden . Are you all right now ?
Yeah . I really have to thank you .
I 'm sorry I ruined your day off .
No . Don 't worry about me .
Where are you ?
Remember the kid that hasn 't shown up in school ?
I came to his house .
Yeah .
The thing is , the boy is here . The parents haven 't come home .
I 've been waiting for nearly an hour .
Hey Mariko . Where is that ?
Huh ? Hello ?
Hello Rika ?
Hello ?
Hey , Rika ?
Toshio ?
Toshio ? Are you there ?
Mariko !
Mariko .
Mariko ?
Mariko !
No .
No !